# Akash Deshmukh

🗣 India 🛮 akashdeshmukh3030@gmail.com 🔲 9284011655 🛗 in/akash-deshmukh-95a676229/ 🕳 https://portfolio-p913.vercel.app/

## **SUMMARY**

Motivated, proactive, and hands-on developer with 0-1 years' experience developing and managing information systems for software development and cloud-based companies. Energetic team leader with strong organizational skills and history of driving user-based database design initiatives.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Software Developer Intern | Dwebpixel Technologies | Pune ,Maharashtra | January 2023 - August 2023

- ·Collaborated with a team of developers to identify and fix bugs in existing Android apps, resulting in a 30% improvement in app performance.
- $\cdot$  Implemented new features and functionality into Android apps using React Native Expo, leading to a 15% increase in user engagement.
- · Developed and deployed 5 Android apps for clients using React Native Expo, resulting in a 20% increase in client satisfaction.
- Performed unit, integration, and regression testing to ensure quality of applications.

# Software Developer Intern | AI4M | Pune ,Maharashtra | January 2023 - July 2023

- · Implemented data visualization techniques to present key performance indicators (KPIs) on the dashboard, resulting in a 30% improvement in the traffic of the company's site in data analysis efficiency for clients.
- $\cdot$  Collaborated with cross-functional teams to gather requirements and conduct user testing, ensuring the dashboard met client, Needs and achieved a 95% adoption rate.
- · Developed a user-friendly dashboard using AWS and React, increasing client satisfaction by 20%.
- · Utilized version control software like Github to deploy and maintain code.
- $\cdot$  Completed backend & database programming using Node.js, Python, and MongoDB .

#### **PROJECTS**

## Client Side Web Application | June 2023 - July 2023

- · Implemented SEO strategies and optimized website content, leading to a 20% increase in organic search rankings and driving an additional 1000 monthly visitors.
- · Developed a user-friendly website for a company, resulting in a 50% increase in online traffic within the first month of launch.
- · Collaborated with cross-functional teams to gather requirements, design wireframes, and develop custom features, resulting in a seamless user experience and reducing bounce rate by 40%.

## Face Detection | April 2021 - May 2021

- $\cdot$  Developed and implemented a face recognition model using tenserflow ,resulting in a 95% accuracy rate in detecting and identifying different faces of humans.
- · Utilized axios and Material-UI to optimize the performance of the face recognition model, reducing response time by 40% and increasing processing speed by 50%.
- · Integrate the face recognition model into a ReactJS application, resulting in an improved user interface and seamless user experience.

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor Of Technology ( Production and Industrial Engineering) | National Institute Of Technology ,Kurukshetra | Kurukshetra ,Haryana | 2024 | 8.60 CGPA

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

## CodeRush Challenge | AlgoUniversity | 2023

Secured 75th rank in CodeRush coding challenge

## POSITION OF RESPONSIBILITY

# Tech Team Lead | NIT KKR | INNOVATION AND INCUBATION CENTER | July 2023 - July 2024

- · Led a team of 20 developers in creating innovative features for the app, including an AI-powered resume builder and personalized job recommendations, resulting in a 50% increase in user engagement.
- $\cdot$  Collaborated with outreach team to develop and execute a targeted campaign that resulted in 1000 downloads of the app within the first month of launch.
- Developed and implemented a user-friendly mobile app for students to easily track and manage their job and internship applications, resulting in a 30% increase in application completion rates.

#### **SKILLS**

C,C++, Python(Basic), Data Structures, Algorithms, Oops, DBMS, Computer Networking, HTML5, CSS3,

Javascript(ES6+), ReactJs, NextJs, Material-UI, Bootstrap, Git/Github, NodeJs, ExpressJs, Axios, Redux,

MongoDB, SQL, JSON, AWS, Rract Native, NativeBase,